#### Contact

rameelster@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/rameel-a-c-30935421 (LinkedIn)

#### Top Skills

Microsoft SQL Server Crystal Reports Visual Basic

# Rameel A C

Warehouse Management System Support at M. H. Alshaya Co. United Arab Emirates

### Summary

An IT Professional with 7 years of experience in Microsoft SQL Server Database Administration, Database Security, Performance Tuning, Disaster Recovery and Implementing High Availability with AlwaysOn Availability Groups and Failover Clustering. Hands-on experience in SQL Database Administration activities encompassing database installation, configuration, planning backup & recovery, patch management. Strong ability in performing integrity checks, methods includes configuring the database maintenance plan wizard and DBCC utilities. Also worked with Big Data and NOSQL Databases.

Big Data Administration Skills

Skills in planning hadoop cluster, installation and configuration of single node, Multi node Full Distributed hadoop cluster.

Cluster monitoring, HDFS configuration & administration, cluster maintenance activities like Adding data nodes and task trackers, Secondary name node and metadata backup, Recovering name node. Cluster monitoring

Knowledgable in:

Cluster Monitoring Tools – Nagios and Ganglia NoSQL Databases - MongoDB Eco system – Pig, Hive, Hbase, SQOOP, Flume

## Experience

M. H. Alshaya Co.

Warehouse Management Application Support October 2010 - Present (10 years 1 month)

Dubai

- Understanding the business flow of warehouse operation by involving with Super users, business process owners and end users and documenting them.
- Configure Warehouse number, storage types, storage section
- Responsible for User access to Warehouse Management System

- Provide reports (Crystal) and determined distribution lists for those reports for Receiving and Shipping Operations.
- Reconcile confirmed pick orders in Warehouse Management System with Inventory Management System using BI reports prepared in Oracle Discoverer 10G.
- Generate alerts to specific Users when interface (bridging) errors occurred (EDI monitoring).
- Test and help implement Manhattan WMOS modifications in both Development and Production environments.
- Worked as an active member of the Disaster Recovery and Business Continuity Plan Team.
- Debugging bespoke transactions as part of error resolution.
- Configuring the cross docking functionality ensuring smooth stock flow through the distribution center to retail stores.
- Day to day warehouse operations incident resolution.
- Functional support for picking, packing and shipping issue resolutions.
- Extending database support and involved in troubleshooting and migration
- Closely monitoring database size and disk space in production & development environments
- Actively involved in creating:
- o Backup strategy which includes full, differential and transaction log backups
- o And scheduling maintenance plans (database and log backups & cleanups)
- o Monitoring scripts to provide alert for production issues
- Performing performance tuning using SQL Profiler and Windows Performance Monitor

# Al Reyami Technologies

Programmer

April 2009 - August 2010 (1 year 5 months)

Dubai

- Requirement gathering, Data Migration, Developing Reports, UAT and production implementation.
- Package development for Annual leave salary advance/deduction, Lieu leave, Travel allowance, Payment/Reimbursement.
- Report Design for Person Details, Pay slip report, Cheque Format Print, Bank Transfer Report etc.
- Creating alerts for Employee training Class Expiration, Employee Leave Resumption reminder, Employee passport Expiry Escalation.
- Support related to technical issues in HRMS module.

- Data update on grade change, salary change, position change and organization change.
- Employee data upload passport, visa, contract, contact and address.

Metadata Technologies CRM Technical Consultant July 2007 - March 2009 (1 year 9 months) Dubai

- Provide CRM functional design solutions for customers, including full lifecycle implementation.
- Configure and implement CRM functional modules, encompassing sales planning, order management, account and contact management.
- Conduct detailed analysis sessions with end users and business subject matter experts (SMEs).
- Space monitoring, index defragmentation, update statistics, log shipping between primary production servers and standby
- Supervised installation and configuration of Soffront ver.8.6 in windows 2003 server
- Managed designing of:
- o Forms Product Enquiry, Opportunity, Offer, Leads, Employee, etc.
- o Business workflow for user groups for objects like leads, account, ticket, activities, and opportunities
- Established dashboards for users & user groups and mail server to send email campaigns & notifications

#### Education

Sree Narayana College, Kannur

Visvesvaraya Technological University
Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Computer Science